# Spencer J. Hulse

hulse.spencer@gmail.com | 423-653-7820 | Chattanooga, TN 37404

GitHub: https://github.com/SpencerHulse

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/spencer-hulse-987521223/ Portfolio: https://spencer-hulse-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Full-stack developer with an education in psychology and experience as an editor and writer. Received web development training through the Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp, during which time skills in areas including the MERN stack, SQL, and Redux were developed. I have created websites, including an e-commerce site and property listing site. Other skills include written and oral communication, the ability to pick up new technologies quickly, and logical problem-solving. Combined with dedication and adaptability, the goal is to push ahead and keep learning and succeeding in the field.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5

**Applications:** GitHub

Tools: Bootstrap, jQuery, MERN, PWAs, Redux

#### **PROJECTS**

# E-commerce Site | Independent Project

Full-stack Developer

- The project took experiences I learned from a similar project and took it to the next level, fully integrating stripe and providing a robust user experience and admin dashboard with weekly sales statistics
- Role: Led the project with another developer, completely taking care of the back-end of the application and doing most of the front-end functionality, including custom hooks, responsiveness, and state

Deployed Application: <a href="https://sellouts.herokuapp.com/">https://sellouts.herokuapp.com/</a>

GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/SpencerHulse/sellouts">https://github.com/SpencerHulse/sellouts</a>

## E-commerce Site | Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp

Full-stack Developer

- The project involved creating an e-commerce site from the ground up, utilizing some basic Stripe setup, Redux Toolkit, and GraphQL with Apollo Server
- Role: I took lead on the backend, a majority of the React components and functionality, and connecting the front-end and back-end of the application

Deployed Application: <a href="https://n-sense.herokuapp.com/">https://n-sense.herokuapp.com/</a>

GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/SpencerHulse/n-sense">https://github.com/SpencerHulse/n-sense</a>

# Property Listing Application | Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp

Lead Back-end Developer

• A full-stack application that allows landlords to list rental properties

 Role: Took the lead on the back-end development, taking care of almost all of the routes, JS, and database code

Deployed Application: https://glacial-temple-16968.herokuapp.com/

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/SpencerHulse/tenantively-maybe-probably

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Freelance Employment**

February 2016 - Present

Writer and Editor

Chattanooga, TN

- Cooperated with many people to help them achieve their own goals while delivering a quality product
- Managed deadlines and actively pursued leads for further projects
- Researched and ensured quality content for more than 200 topics in dozens of fields

#### **Grit Daily**

March 2021 - Present

Writer

Chattanooga, TN

- Write affiliate articles on many products and services
- Research companies and subjects for research articles
- Report on emerging startups and recent funding press releases

#### **Atlas Studios**

May 2019 - April 2020

Content Editor

Chattanooga, TN

- Interacted with a team of more than 30 translators and editors to bring novels from Asia to America
- Edited more than 2000 chapters of translated novels for consistency, quality, and intent
- Monitored other editors to ensure high standards were met

## **EDUCATION**

Vanderbilt University Bootcamp

May 2022

Certificate in Full-stack Development

The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN

May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Psychology